Stephen D'Arcy

3 Carrigmore view Aylesbury Dublin 24

Mobile: 086-7239007 | Email: sdarcy29@hotmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-darcy-gfa-38987167

I have worked within various teams in the financial services sector for the past 7 years. I have achieved QFA/APA status. I have extensive 1st line 2nd line and 3rd line of defence experience in AML/KYC/PEP and sanctions-based operations including transaction monitoring. I have extensive knowledge of several banking systems and Microsoft office suites. I have a keen interest in technology and how it applies to today's business requirements.

Technical Skills:

Outlook
Excel
SQL
Power BI
Word
Access
SharePoint
Tableau

Education:

Tallaght institute of technology 2020 – 2021

Web application development.

Galway/Mayo institute of technology 2018 -2020

Level 8 special purpose award in Business analytics, database design and statistics.

Institute of banking/UCD Sept 2017 – On-going

LCOI Compliance PDC 1 Completed.

Institute of Banking/UCD Sept 2013 - Jan 2016

Employment History:

Citibank Dublin November 2019 – Present Senior Business Analyst

- Perform in-depth evaluation to identify and resolve complex problems.
- Perform data analysis on client lds in production environments.
- To interpret business requirements from across the business and implement change requests.
- Write and update business requirements documents and statements of requirements.
- Perform PVT and UAT testing as and where required in the lifecycle of the change request.
- Write PVT files in H2H and XML format for PVT testing.
- Influence decisions through advice and counsel as well as facilitate services to others in area.
- Liaises with multiple teams across the Operations department.
- Assume informal and formal leadership role within team as well as coach and train new recruits.
- Appropriately assess risk when business decisions are made, demonstrating consideration for the firm's reputation and safeguarding Citigroup, its clients and assets, by driving compliance with applicable laws, rules and regulations, adhering to Policy, applying sound ethical judgment regarding personal behaviour, conduct and business practices, and escalating, managing and reporting control issues with transparency.

Citibank Dublin
March 2018 – October 2019
Senior sanctions compliance analyst

- Analyse comparative data, prepare, and present regional and global reports related to sanctions risk assessments, and monitoring of sanctions related issues and escalations with senior management and global partners.
- Support a specialised team of Independent Compliance Risk Management (ICRM) officers responsible for program execution activities.
- Support all EMEA businesses by acting in an advisory sanction's compliance capacity, acting as the Level 3 escalation point for complex sanctions compliance escalations including transaction monitoring, mergers, and acquisitions among other instruments.

- Contributes to the design and maintenance of a comprehensive written ICRM Sanctions Framework (standards and policies)
- Monitors adherence to Citi's Global Sanctions Policy and relevant procedures; is up to date on key Sanctions regulatory changes, key enforcement actions and related industry trends.
- Overseas adherence to procedures and processes, to ensure compliance with policies ensuring that front line units meet required standards.
- Interacts with relevant teams to raise awareness of Sanctions trends, emerging issues, remedial actions, or enhancements to the program.
- Draft and edit sanctions-related reference materials and participate in sanctions training programs.

Achievements:

I have developed new SharePoint sites to eliminate the need for large volumes of email queries being sent in from the business.

I have successfully completed UAT testing on behalf of my team for the implementation of a new payments screening system to the Ukraine and Russia.

AIB Group
June 2016 – March 2018
Financial crime and AML sanctions.

- Ensure all 2nd level queries and payments are fully investigated and ensure there are no sanction breaches or compliance issues.
- Liaise with internal & external stakeholders regarding Financial Crime matters
- To answer all mails in a timely and accurate manner.
- To make sure all internal systems are regularly checked on OFAC, EUR-LEX AND HM Treasury updates
- Capture and record accurate investigative findings to support decision taken.
- Investigating accounts/policies/products where potentially suspicious account activity is identified.
- Use several systems to exclude potential persons and entities for matches against various world and European sanctions and compliance lists.

Bank of Ireland July 2015 - July 2016 Risk / AML Payments Investigator

- Ensure sanction matches/ suspicious activity is identified in a timely manner.
- Liaise with internal & external stakeholders regarding Financial Crime matters

- Capture and record accurate investigative findings to support decision taken.
- Investigating accounts/policies/products where potentially suspicious account activity is identified.
- Gather intelligence and investigate potentially sanctioned payments/suspicious activity.
- Provide day-to-day support to the Manager in assisting on-going compliance with regulatory requirements.
- Test training courses regarding sanctions awareness and AML protocols.
- Some supervisory roles Delegating daily tasks Preparing daily and monthly stats for manager meetings – Assisting with team Rota's.

Bank of Ireland Sept 2013 – July 2015

Business online (several positions held as below)

Customer Service Agent

- Answered calls from business customers regarding queries on their account.
- Assisted with logging in to the business online system.
- Advised on technical procedures to help restore online functionality for customers.

Query management team

- Locate missing payments for customers and advise on the status of the payments.
- Advise customers on the reason for payments being returned or rejected.
- Making follow up calls to customers to issue passwords or log in details.
- Working with other payment departments to assure all proper documentation has been sent out to customers.
- Assisted with general troubleshooting and access issues for staff surrounding annual leave and the SAP payment platform.

Business on Line 2nd Level Technical Support

- Lead a small team that would follow up on logged calls from customers who
 were continuing to have difficulties logging on to the online system after 1st
 level help.
- Compile reports from the customer management systems on workload for management.

Business online Fraud Helpdesk

- Extract information from International and SEPA payment reports to locate possible fraudulent activity.
- Checking business online payments for group operations to verify their authenticity.
- Contacting customers where their account has been blocked due to possible viruses on their laptops/P. C's.

- Reporting all possible fraud to the relevant departments as well as putting recalls on the funds.
- Some supervisory roles Delegating daily tasks Preparing daily and monthly stats for manager meetings.